This time it's war.
Aliens is a action, thriller, science fiction film directed by James Cameron.
Ripley, the sole survivor of the Nostromo's deadly encounter with the monstrous Alien,
returns to Earth after drifting through space in hypersleep for 57 years.
Although her story is initially met with skepticism, she agrees to
accompany a team of Colonial Marines back to LV-426.
Ripley, played by Sigourney Weaver.
Newt, played by Carrie Henn.
Corporal Hicks, played by Michael Biehn.
Burke, played by Paul Reiser.
Bishop, played by Lance Henriksen.
Private Hudson, played by Bill Paxton.
Aliens is a 1986 science fiction-action film
written and directed by James Cameron.
It is the sequel to the 1979 science fiction horror film
Alien, and the second film in the Alien franchise.
Set in the far future, it stars Sigourney Weaver as Ellen Ripley,
the sole survivor of an alien attack on her ship.
When communications are lost with a human colony on the moon where her crew first encountered the alien
creatures, Ripley agrees to return to the site with a unit of Colonial Marines to investigate.
Michael Biehn, Paul Reiser, Lance Henriksen, and Carrie
Henn are featured in supporting roles.
Despite the success of Alien, its sequel took years to develop due to lawsuits, a lack
of enthusiasm from 20th Century Fox, and repeated management changes.
Although relatively inexperienced, Cameron was hired to write a story for Aliens in 1983 on the
strength of his scripts for The Terminator (1984) and Rambo: First Blood Part II (1985).
The project stalled again until new Fox executive
Lawrence Gordon pursued a sequel.
On an approximately $18.5 million budget, Aliens began principal
photography in September 1985 and concluded in January 1986.
The film's development was tumultuous and rife with conflicts
between Cameron and the British crew at Pinewood Studios.
The difficult shoot affected the composer, James Horner, who
was given little time to record the music.
Aliens was released on July 18, 1986, to critical acclaim.
Reviewers praised its action, but some criticized
the intensity of certain scenes.
Weaver's performance garnered consistent praise along with
those of Bill Paxton and Jenette Goldstein.
The film received several awards and nominations, including an Academy Award nomination for Best
Actress for Weaver at a time when the science-fiction genre was generally overlooked.
It earned $131.1–183.3 million during its theatrical run, making it
one of the highest-grossing films of 1986 worldwide.
Aliens is now considered among the greatest films of the 1980s, and among the best science
fiction, action, and sequel films ever made, often deemed equal to or better than Alien.
It is credited with expanding the franchise's scope with additions to the
series' backstory and factions such as the Colonial Marines.
It inspired a variety of merchandise, including
video games, comic books and toys.
It was followed by two sequels: Alien 3 (1992) and Alien Resurrection (1997), a
prequel film, Alien: Romulus (2024), and a TV series, Alien: Earth (2025).
The film explores themes of android, space marine,
extraterrestrial technology, spaceman, space travel.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.